So here we are back at our blog,
回到我们的博客页面
and here we can see our block homepage is setup a little different.
这里我们可以看到首页有一点不同
Right now, it just has one column with all the content.
到目前为止 所有的内容都展示在一列里面
That's because when doing responsive design or mobile design,
因为当你做移动端设计或响应式设计时
it's always, always, always important to start first with the smallest setting.
最最重要的是从最小最简单的部分开始
Trust me, or you can go at it on your own, but by far,
相信我 你可以有你自己的方式 但是
the most sane way to do this is to first that up what you want
这里比较明智的方式是先在较小的屏幕上
your content to look like on the smallest screen and that work up from there.
显示出所有你想要显示的内容 然后在此基础上进行开发
So in this example,
在这个例子中
what I've done is I've started by setting up our container,
我从一个 container 容器开始
and if you look here,
如果你查看这里
I have the grid template areas setup as just one straight column down with a header,
在 grid-template-areas 中 我只是简单的将每个区域设置成了一列
a sidebar, a main,
一个 header 一个 sidebar 一个 main 区域
and a footer right here.
和一个 footer 区域
Here, I've assigned the different grid areas accordingly to the elements,
这里 我将不同的元素放置进了对应的网格区域内
but then down here,
不过在底部
I've set a new rule.
我设置了一条新的规则
Here I'm saying, if the screen is wide enough.
如果屏幕达到一定宽度
So if the minimum width of our browser screen,
这里也就是屏幕的最小宽度
the device is telling us that the information is greater than 900 pixels,
如果超过了 900 像素
what I want to happen is I've created a new grid template area.
我们就会创建一个新的 grid-template-areas
So below 900 pixels,
所以当屏幕宽度低于 900 像素时
this is our grid template area,
采用这个 grid-template-areas
and then just using the names,
同样地
I've said what I want it to look like if it's more than 900 pixels.
当屏幕宽度超过 900 像素时 我们使用下面这种方式
So if we come over here and we see,
我们可以来试一试
if we just drag this over, did you see that?
如果我们拖动改变屏幕宽度 看见没？
Right at 900 pixels,
在 900 像素这个点
it makes the switch for us.
页面会发生变化
So here I have a full wide screen layout.
这里我们有一个完整宽度的布局
I have plenty of room for my blog post on the side,
有足够的空间显示 sidebar 区域
my content, my header and footer,
content 内容区域 header 以及 footer 区域
and then as I go in and I start to lose room,
随着我们不断缩小屏幕空间
the switch happens, just like that.
样式会发生变化
One important thing to notice is that,
一个需要特别注意的事情是
I have my media query at the bottom of my code.
我将媒体查询放在了代码底部
It's always a good idea to set it up this way,
这通常是一个比较好的方式
because the way CSS is red is straight down.
因为 CSS 代码是从上到下的顺序
So it's going to go through like this first and pick up all of
所以你可以先设置
this inherently for under 900 pixels,
当屏幕低于 900 像素时的样式
and then when it goes over 900 pixels,
然后是高于 900 像素时的样式
the only rules that will override are the ones I've placed in here.
放置在这里的规则将会覆盖之前的样式
So I'm going to remove this for a sec so you can see that it actually has its own object.
现在我们先删除掉这里面的代码
The keyword is @media, let's write one out,
这里的关键字是 @media 让我们重新写一下
@media, then @media takes a parameter,
@media @media 会接受参数
we've been using min-width.
我们使用 min-width
Then let's say we actually wanted to not happen till the screen for a little wider.
这次我们设置为屏幕更宽一些时再改变样式
We could say at 1100 pixels we want it to happen, our brackets,
设置为 1100 像素作为我们的断点
and then inside here,
然后在括号内部
these are the CSS rules that are going to apply when this happens.
放置好我们想要应用的 CSS 规则
So here I've put my code in at 1100 pixels.
现在我们已经设置好了在 1100 像素时的样式
So now, nothing should happen at 900,
所以当我们把屏幕拖动到 900 像素时
but at 1100 pixels,
并不会有变化 但是在达到 1100 像素
we should see the widescreen format take hold.
宽屏的样式就生效了
So now, we go a little wider and at 11, we see it happened.
所以现在我们需要在 1100 像素时样式才会发生变化
This is because we've used a media query with a break-point.
因为我们在媒体查询中设置的断点就是这样
That's just one example of what you can do with media queries.
这就是一个关于使用媒体查询的一个例子
Now, you try some on your own and then we'll come back and I'll
现在你可以先自己动手试试 然后我们会回来看看
show you what we can do by setting up two media queries,
如何同时使用 2 种媒体查询方式
so that there are three possible layouts,
这样会有 3 种可能的布局样式
one for small screens,
一种针对小屏幕
one for medium screens,
一种针对中型屏幕
and one for big screens. Good luck.
和一种专门针对大型屏幕的样式 祝你好运